Chase Seeberger

Salem, Oregon, United States

chase.seeberger@gmail.com

2089955987

linkedin.com/in/chaseseeberger

Summary

3 years experience in warehouse operations, 1 year experience in warehouse management, and 1 year of experience in IT developing applications.

Built an IT department for a family retail business using frameworks such as Vue 3, React, ASP.NET, express.js, Bootstrap, and Tailwind CSS.

Developed 2 internal applications to manage rental products and improve employee productivity.

Developed 1 public facing website which replaced an expensive and outdated website.

Experience

IT Specialist

Tuxgear Inc

Dec 2021 - Present (2 years 4 months)

IT Specialist is my current and second position I have worked in at Tuxgear Inc. Tuxgear Inc is a family owned and operated retail business specializing in renting and selling suits, tuxedos, and related formal attire. As IT Specialist I had many roles to fill as well as three big projects I developed to help the business succeed and compete in the retail industry.

The first project I developed was an inventory system to help the company manage product across the store and several storage units. The goal for this system is to keep track of product data for approximately 2000 products to prevent over stocking or under stocking of product. It is still in use today helping the company save money by supplying data that makes ordering product more accurate and efficient.

The second project I developed was a rental management program to help the company manage their product rentals for events such as weddings and proms. The program needed to minimize errors, increase efficiency, and have a professional appearance. The project reached its first production version in November of 2023 and is currently being used in the companies store front. It has helped the company transfer from a paper system to fully digital.

The third project I am currently developing and is planned to be released in March of 2023. It is a public facing website that allows its users to view store product, reserve a rental package, and view information about current sales, business hours, and frequently asked questions. The goal for this website is to have an admin that allows employees of the company to login and make changes to the website without the need for a developer to edit code.

Outside of these three project I have tasks that I perform as necessary. Some of these tasks include: fixing problems that may occur with computers, internet, printers, or other related technology, training new employees on systems that the company uses, and filling in roles when other employees are busy or gone.

Barber

REDLANS GENTLEMENS GROOMING LLC

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021 (10 months)

At Redlan's Gentlemens Grooming I was employed as a full time barber. I had several roles at the barbershop including some of the following: servicing clients, customer service, maintaining a clean working environment, and communicating with clients, co-workers, and management.

Servicing clients was the biggest role I had as a barber. The main services I offered were haircuts, beard trims, and shaves.

Communication was the most important skill I learned during my barbering experience. Although technical skill was a critical component of barbering services I learned it can often be bottlenecked by communication. My definition of an excellent services is not shared with every person that sits in my chair. A client can leave my chair dissatisfied because I did not understand their expectations for the service. Communicating with my client before, during, and after services was a critical skill of my barbering experience that is still a part of my personality today.

Customer service was a constant ongoing process while in a barbershop. Handling phone calls, scheduling appointments, and communicating with clients are some examples of customer service situations I was in charge of daily.

Due to the type of services you are performing on your clients cleanliness is not only required by the barbershop management but is enforced by law and has serious consequences if not followed properly.

Although the bare bones of barbering is cutting hair and beard trims a large and diverse skill set was required to succeed.

Warehouse Team Member

Tuxgear Inc

May 2016 - Jan 2019 (2 years 9 months)

Working at Tuxgear Inc. forged my passion for entrepreneurship and gave me an amazing insight to what it means to be an entrepreneur. Tuxgear is a family ran, ecommerce oriented, online retail business specializing in the sale of formal wear for people of all ages. My role in the business was within the warehouse department. Specifically, I was apart of a team with the task of shipping out all orders directly to the customer. One of the bonuses of being apart of a family run business is having the ability to see every part of the business work together and connect to make a system that outputs all the needs of the business. Having this ability is what sparked the passion of entrepreneurship within me and formed the path for my future.

Dishwasher

Express Cafe

Jul 2015 - Nov 2015 (5 months)

Working as a dishwasher at Express Cafe was my first job I obtained. I picked up the job when I was just fourteen years old in middle school. Working here helped me develop a work schedule early on in my life along with learning the importance of money and savings. The position was very straightforward, I worked as a weekend dishwasher, coming in every Saturday and on some Sundays. It was an amazing first work experience, but I only worked there for a handful of months before leaving to focus on my schoolwork.

Education



Computer Science @ University of Oregon

Web Development Bootcamp, Computer Programming Oct 2023 - Apr 2024

Paul Mitchell the School-Boise

Barber License, Barbering/Barber

Jun 2020 - Feb 2021

Following the pandemic I decided to get licensed in barbering to support myself financially. This school was the first step that I took which eventually lead me to acquiring my license in barbering from the state of Idaho in February of 2021.

Skills

IT Integration • Computer Repair • Software Development • Rental Management • Coding Experience • Customer Satisfaction • Customer Retention • Phone Etiquette • Communication • Marketing